Richard W. Vuduc

Curriculum Vitæ

2007-2013

My research program designs scalable parallel algorithms and software for computational science, data analysis, and data mining. This work has been broadly applied to blood flow simulation, advanced manufacturing, and mining of astronomical data, among others.

△ | 266 Ferst Drive, Atlanta, Georgia 30332-0765

+1 (404) 385-3355

□ richie@gatech.edu

vuduc.org | hpcgarage.org

Professional Service

Chair SIAM Activity Group on Supercomputing

(elected) (SIAM/SC), 2018–2020

Vice Chair Technical Papers

ACM/IEEE Conf. Supercomp. (SC), 2016

Co-chair Program Committee

ACM Principles & Practice of Parallel Programming (PPoPP), 2013

Education

1997–2004 **Ph.D.**, Computer Science

University of California, Berkeley

1993–1997 **B.S.**, with honors, Computer Science

Cornell University

Experience

Georgia Institute of Technology

School of Computational Science and Engineering (CSE)

Associate Chair & Dir. of Grad. Programs 2013–Present Associate Professor 2013–Present

Assistant Professor Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory (LLNL)

Postdoctoral Scholar 2004–2007

Institute for Defense Analyses (IDA)

Research Intern (summers) 1994–1996

Awards and Honors (selected)

2015	Winner, Best Paper
	IEEE Int'l. Par. & Dist. Proc. Symp. (IPDPS)

- 2013 Lockheed Martin Excellence in Teaching Award
- 2012 **Winner, Best Paper** *SIAM Conf. Data Mining (SDM)*
 - 10 Winner, Gordon Bell Prize
- 2010 **Winner, Gordon Bell Prize**ACM/IEEE Conf. Supercomputing (SC)
- 2010 Outstanding Junior Faculty Research Award College of Computing, Georgia Institute of Technology
- 2010 Winner, Best Paper
 IEEE Int'l. Par. & Distr. Proc. Symp. (IPDPS)
- 2010 CAREER Award

National Science Foundation

- 2009 **Finalist, Best Paper** *ACM/IEEE Conf. Supercomputing (SC)*
- 2009 **Winner, R&D 100 Award** *R&D Magazine*
- 2009 **Invited Member**DARPA Computer Science Study Group (CSSG)
- 2009 "Hottest" (most downloaded) Article [link] Parallel Computing (ParCo)

Invited Keynotes & Talks

Keynote Int'l. Mtg. HPC for Computational Science

(VECPAR), 2018

Keynote Int'l. Symp. Memory Systems

(MEMSYS), 2016

Keynote SIAM Parallel Processing (PP), 2014

Keynote Scalable Hierarchical Algorithms for

eXtreme-Scale Computing (SHAX-C) King Abdullah Univ. Sci. Tech. (KAUST), 2012

Publications (selected) [Google Scholar Page]

• J. Li, J. Sun, R. Vuduc. "HiCOO: Hierarchical storage of sparse tensors." *SC* 2018.

Finalist, Best Student Paper

- S. Karamati, J. Young, R. Vuduc. "An energy-efficient single-source shortest path algorithm." *IPDPS* 2018.
- P. Sao, X. Li, R. Vuduc. "A communication-avoiding 3D LU factorization algorithm for sparse matrices." IPDPS 2018.
- Y. You, J. Demmel, K. Czechowski, L. Song, R. Vuduc. "CA-SVM: Communication-avoiding support vector machines on clusters." *IPDPS* 2015.
 Best Paper
- K. Czechowski, V. W. Lee, E. Grochowski, R. Ronen, R. Singhal, P. Dubey, R. Vuduc. "Improving the energy-efficiency of big cores." *ISCA* 2014.
- J. Choi, D. Bedard, R. Fowler, R. Vuduc. "A roofline model of energy." *IPDPS* 2013. [PDF]
- D. Lee, R. Vuduc, and A. G. Gray. "A distributed kernel summation framework for general-dimension machine learning." *SDM* 2012. [PDF] **Best paper**
- A. Rahimian et al. "Petascale direct numerical simulation of blood flow on 200k cores and heterogeneous architectures." *SC* 2010. [www] **Gordon Bell Prize**